<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="_mainpage" xml:lang="en-US">

<para><anchor xml:id="_index_1mainpage"/> <emphasis role="bold">ABI version 10</emphasis></para>

<para>The EVMC is the low-level ABI between Ethereum Virtual Machines (EVMs) and Ethereum Clients. On the EVM-side it supports classic EVM1 and <link xlink:href="https://github.com/ewasm/design">ewasm</link>. On the Client-side it defines the interface for EVM implementations to access Ethereum environment and state.</para>
<section xml:id="_index_1guides">
<title>Guides</title>

<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><link linkend="_hostguide">Host Implementation Guide</link></para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para><link linkend="_vmguide">VM Implementation Guide</link></para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>
</section>
<section xml:id="_index_1versioning">
<title>Versioning</title>

<para>The EVMC project uses <link xlink:href="https://semver.org">Semantic Versioning</link>. The version format is <computeroutput>MAJOR.MINOR.PATCH</computeroutput>.</para>

<para>The <emphasis>MAJOR</emphasis> version number is also referenced as the <emphasis role="bold">EVMC ABI version</emphasis>. This ABI version is available to VM and Host implementations by <link linkend="_group__EVMC_1gga06fc87d81c62e9abb8790b6e5713c55ba1db9144f8af4e62865f0c003c07a02bc">EVMC_ABI_VERSION</link>. For example EVMC 3.2.1 would have ABI version 3 and therefore this project release can be referenced as EVMC ABIv3 or just EVMC 3. Every C ABI breaking change requires increasing the <emphasis>MAJOR</emphasis> version number.</para>

<para>The releases with <emphasis>MINOR</emphasis> version change allow adding new API features and modifying the language bindings API. Backward incompatible API changes are allowed but should be avoided if possible.</para>

<para>The releases with <emphasis>PATCH</emphasis> should only include bug fixes. Exceptionally, API changes are allowed when required to fix a broken feature.</para>
</section>
<section xml:id="_index_1modules">
<title>Modules</title>

<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><link linkend="_group__EVMC">EVMC</link> – the main component that defines API for VMs and Clients (Hosts).</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para><link linkend="_namespaceevmc">EVMC C++ API</link> – the wrappers and bindings for C++.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para><link linkend="_group__loader">EVMC Loader</link> – the library for loading VMs implemented as Dynamically Loaded Libraries (DLLs, shared objects).</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para><link linkend="_group__helpers">EVMC Helpers</link> – a collection of utility functions for easier integration with EVMC.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para><link linkend="_group__instructions">EVM Instructions</link> – the library with collection of metrics for EVM1 instruction set.</para>
</listitem><listitem>
<para><link linkend="_vmtester">EVMC VM Tester</link> – the EVMC-compatibility testing tool for VM implementations.</para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>
</section>
<section xml:id="_index_1bindings">
<title>Language bindings</title>
<section xml:id="_index_1autotoc_md0">
<title>Go</title>

<para><literallayout><computeroutput>import&#32;&quot;github.com/ethereum/evmc/bindings/go/evmc&quot;
</computeroutput></literallayout> </para>
</section>
</section>
</chapter>
